I decided to cover both open problems in
deep reinforcement learning and how to
do deep RL research. Cool. Um so let's
start with uh part one uh and talking
about open problems and frontiers in
deep reinforcement learning. Uh I'm
going to break this into a few different
categories. Uh the first is challenges
on defining the problem setup. The
second is challenges in methods and the
third is challenges in deployment and
evaluation. I should also mention that
this will not be exhaustive. There's
many problems and many uh open
challenges in uh in deep reinforcement
learning. I'm just picking out some of
the ones that I think um I've either
gotten questions about quite a bit um or
some of the problems that I think are
the most exciting and the most
interesting.
Cool. Um so let's dive in. Uh and in
particular in terms of um some of the
challenges in how we set up the deep RL
problem. Uh we've seen a lot of
successes in domains like games, math
reasoning, coding problems where you can
very easily define the reward. You can
very easily easily verify whether or not
the reinforcement learning system did
the correct thing. Uh which is great. Uh
but in many real world scenarios uh
rewards don't exist or rewards are very
delayed. Uh and this introduces
challenges in the typical problem
setting. And so for example uh let's
think about language models for chat
bots. Uh right now we have preference
optimization. And one might actually say
that preference optimization for chat
bots seems to work quite well. uh we're
able to actually deploy reinforcement
learning at scale. There's actually uh
pretty big problems with preference
optimization. And as one example, there
was this research paper by Charma Tong
that was evaluating
how much um kind of evaluating what
preferences people are giving. And the
x-axis is the probability um that a
preference uh that a response with a
given feature is preferred when all else
is equal. And there's different uh
things here on the left axis. And the
things that were most preferred in the
human preferences were whether the uh it
was something that the human agreed with
and whether or not the response was
confident. Uh so essentially the things
that people are giving preferences for
are whether or not um it kind of the
language model response is something
that's confidently saying uh something
and whether that thing that it's saying
agrees with what the person thinks. And
then all the way down here uh is
factuality. And so they're actually
caring about whether it's confident more
than whether or not the response is
actually correct or true.
Uh and so people aren't actually giving
good preferences. Uh arguably I think we
would want uh language models to be
valuing factuality over things like
confidence. Um and we're more optimizing
for what people kind of want to hear
rather than uh the kinds of responses
that will be good.
Now, if you also think about preference
optimization for personalization, for
example, uh we might want to develop
language models that are um that that
are kind of telling people what they
want to hear and the kinds of
recommendations, for example, that are
closely personalized to their interests
and their beliefs. Uh but on the flip
side, if we personalize these kinds of
models for the many people that use
these models, then it might lead to
polarization and people who um for
example have extreme beliefs rather than
being exposed to a wide range of
beliefs. And so even something like
personalization may not intrinsically be
what we want to optimize for. Um and at
the end of the day, there's typically
multiple things that we do care about
optimizing for. and balancing those
different objectives that may actually
compete with each other ends up being a
very challenging problem.
Um so this whole kind of realm of how do
we define rewards and the kind of
objective as a whole for language models
uh is in many ways there's a lot of
progress but it's still a really
challenging problem.
Um now separate from language models
there's also robotics. Um right now in
robotics either you have binary rewards
uh in the real world or if in simulation
you might have handshaped rewards where
you define different terms for what you
want uh this ends up being takes a lot
of effort ends up being fairly
challenging or takes a lot of labeling
uh annotations
um and even then even when you have
human annotations uh it can be tricky to
judge rewards. And so, for example, if
you were to look at these shirts um that
were each folded by a robot, uh if you
were to think about which shirt was um
folded the best um and or try to give
rewards for these shirt folds, it's
rather tricky to figure out how you
might reward um different mistakes like
different amounts of crinkleness um kind
of whether or not the shirt is offc
center or not. Uh it's generally a very
ambiguous problem and hard even for
people to think about how to provide
rewards for these systems.
>> [snorts]
>> Um, another example, uh, let's think
about YouTube recommendations. Uh, what
I mean here is if when you're on
YouTube, uh, there's recommendations for
a next video to watch after watching
your current video. And these
recommendations are, uh, there's an
algorithm that kind of selects uh, what
these recommendations should be. Uh now
we don't know have exact details on how
this algorithm works but there was a
research paper um that that actually was
talking a little bit about how uh they
do these recommendations. Um and as you
might expect when they do these
recommendations they want to optimize
for engagement which is like whether or
not you actually clicked on the
recommendation. And if you clicked on
the recommendation, that was probably a
good recommendation. And also
satisfaction, which is that after you
clicked on that, if you actually liked
the video, then that's also a good sign
that it was a good recommendation. Um,
so this all seems reasonable.
Uh but another thing that was mentioned
in the research paper was that the
combination of these metrics for the
reward function was actually manually
tuned by a person uh rather than
something that is designed
automatically. This kind of also goes to
show um kind of the challenge in
actually defining these kinds of reward
functions when we don't know like how
best to balance these kinds of
objectives.
Um,
we talked a bit about math reasoning. If
we want to take those advances and apply
them to broader scientific
experimentation and reasoning, you often
don't necessarily know what the final
answer should be.
And so, um, even training on math
reasoning, you might see some transfer
to scientific reasoning. Um, but if you
want to train on a broader set of
scientific reasoning problems, uh, this
sort of verification becomes
challenging. Um the last thing I'll
mention along these sorts of rewards and
and verification uh is that if we think
about how humans learn, uh humans often
learn by like rolling around on the
floor playing with random toys. Uh and
it seems like uh they're not just
optimizing for one particular task. Uh
they're optimizing well who knows what
they're optimizing for. Um maybe
machines uh could for example we could
develop algorithms that would allow
machines to explore in this way. um
potentially optimizing for learning,
potentially optimizing for exploration.
Um and this is certainly an open
problem.
Cool. Um so that's on the problem setup.
Now let's talk a little bit about
challenges on the method side.
So um the first topic I wanted to bring
up was leveraging prior data or
knowledge. So there's a lot of
circumstances where we're not starting
reinforcement learning from scratch and
we have some prior data, some prior
knowledge about what is best to explore.
And the default tool for leveraging
previous knowledge and data is to use
pre-trained model weights or to
initialize your replay buffer with any
previous data that you have.
But this tool doesn't extend to all
sorts of scenarios we might care about.
Um there might be scenarios where we
have more abstract prior knowledge.
Maybe we have some knowledge that we
read from news articles that isn't kind
of in the typical data format and we
want to incorporate those facts into our
model. Maybe we have some hints uh that
could be helpful for solving a problem.
Um and even separate from that, if we
think about this kind of paradigm of
using pre-training and initialized data
sets, uh there's scenarios where this
might actually be too constraining.
Uh and so as one example um here's a
research paper uh by Baladol in 2023 um
and they introduced a method that was
studying using prior demonstration data
with reinforcement learning and the
method that they introduced uh they
initialized the the buffer but they
actually didn't pre-train the weights
and they found that pre-training the
weights did worse than not pre-training
the weights. Uh and so this kind of
suggests that like there might be
scenarios where using kind of
pre-trained weights or using uh
pre-trained data sets might actually be
too constraining on our model. Um as one
example of this, if you have a
pre-trained model, um the the output
layer of that pre-trained model might
have converged to something fairly
deterministic. And then if you're trying
to learn something new or adapt it in a
new way, then that last uh layer might
not actually be exploring in a good way.
Um so that's one example of why you
might see worse performance if you don't
uh if you initialize your weights um
with some previous neural network. Um
and arguably in language models, uh
perhaps reinforcement learning works
quite well because pre-trained models
often have a very diverse distribution
over output tokens.
And in terms of leveraging prior data
and knowledge and and also being able to
go beyond it, I think that this question
is really important for thinking about
how language models can solve problems
that humans haven't solved. Uh because
they probably should build upon the
knowledge in the pre-trained data sets,
but they also need to think about how to
go beyond that and not be too
constrained by what the pre-trained
model might say.
Uh, and it's also um quite useful for
thinking about how robots or autonomous
vehicles might learn how to do things
faster and more reliably than what
humans do. And perhaps if we constrain
too much to the pre-trained uh knowledge
or the prior knowledge, then they might
not be able to surpass human abilities
in terms of speed or reliability.
And so I think generally these two
questions are really fascinating uh and
things that we've seen some um some
suggestions that reinforcement learning
can do this. Uh and it's certainly one
of the most promising tools for going
beyond what humans can do. Uh but lots
of interesting and open work to do
there.
Now one question I've gotten quite a bit
is whether we can leverage world models
and video generation models for uh
robotics and control. And we've seen
some really impressive uh results
especially recently from video
generation models where they clearly
have a lot of rich knowledge about the
world like how cooking um on a stove
works. Uh how typing on a keyboard works
and how that might look like if the
keyboard was made of gummy bears. Um and
also how things like even walking at an
abstract level work. And so it seems
like this sort knowledge should be
really useful for learning behavior.
Um, but there's actually a lot of nuance
and a lot of challenges with using these
kinds of models.
Uh, as an example, if [snorts] you train
a action conditioned video generation
model, so a model that takes as input
the current image and future actions and
predicts future video. And if you train
that on demonstrations and rollouts from
one policy
and then you evaluate a new policy's
actions
on um with that model and evaluate
whether or not that those actions lead
to good outcomes,
then you these actions won't necessarily
be represented in the data that the
model was trained on and as a result the
model often will make inaccurate
predictions for these actions. It might
be um if most of the data set is
demonstrations then it will predict a
video that corresponds to correctly
doing the task even if these actions did
not lead to a correct outcome. And
generally these models have very little
data of for example like narrowly making
a mistake um or making mistakes that are
very different from the kinds of
mistakes that humans make.
Um the other thing here is that even
small physical inaccuracies can lead to
poor performance. And so a lot of times
these videos look really really good. Uh
they look like they might be accurate
but that doesn't mean that the physics
the underlying physics is actually
accurate.
Now I think that there's solutions here.
Um one possible solution is to try to
train on data from lots of different
policies with this kind of approach with
the hopes that that will lead to enough
coverage over action distributions to
leverage these models.
Uh and then the second possible solution
is that we might be able to use these
video generation models in other ways.
Uh for as and as one example of that um
maybe instead of training this sort of
physical model of the future um we could
generate for example what should um what
should the video what should the kind of
future video look like um not
conditioned on actions. And if we train
this only on demonstrations,
then for example, we could predict
future video and kind of plan out how to
accomplish the task in the future in
video space and then run a goal
condition policy uh using the predicted
video.
Um, and something like this kind of
sidesteps the challenge of this sort of
out of distribution action problem
because you're only using the model for
um for a form of planning where you're
thinking through like what is a good
outcome in the future rather than
thinking through what is the outcome of
specific actions.
Cool. And then the third thing on the
method side uh the third challenge that
I'll talk about is thinking about
scaling.
So
on the scaling front, uh we've seen
large scale RL succeed uh with language
models and that's actually really
exciting to see. Uh but there's still
shortcomings there. So a lot of language
model RL is still fairly is considering
problems that are still fairly short
horizon or um extremely online like
using like generating rollouts of the
model every single iteration.
And um as an example of this, if we're
doing preference optimization, typically
we consider this single turn dialogue
setting where we're getting rewards just
for our next response rather than trying
to reward the outcome of the full
conversation.
And this means that it's a shorter
horizon problem. It means you don't have
to have a human in the loop of data
collection to generate those those
dialogue conversations. Um and so this
makes the problem um easier. uh which is
good to make the problem easier but it
means that in there if there are
scenarios where you have longer horizon
problems or you need a human in the loop
of data collection uh that becomes a lot
more challenging to do at large scale.
Um, as another example, if we think
about reasoning for math problems, uh,
this relies on a very large number of
online samples from the model interleved
with policy updates.
And there are some scenarios where it's
actually really hard to collect that
sort of like very online data interled
with policy updates, especially if
collecting data involves interfacing
with humans or interfacing with the
physical world.
So
towards this end uh if we wanted to
think about longer horizon problems uh
and efficiently learning uh tools like
value functions should be really useful
and I think we have yet to see um we've
seen some signs of life in training
value functions at large scale and when
using PO uh we train value functions at
large scale uh but these value functions
are primarily used for reducing gradient
variance and may not be accurate enough
for doing like a full actor critic
update or for selecting actions with
like a Q-learning style objective.
And so um understanding whether we can
scale up value function learning um and
have value functions be accurate enough
for directly optimizing policies uh
something that's pretty interesting to
explore and might be important for
longer horizon problems.
Um and then second I mentioned that on
like very online data collection uh can
be challenging at large scale.
Um, and
as an example of this, um, say that you
are, um, maybe let's say that you're
kind of, um, maybe say that you're like
an autonomous driving company, uh, and
you want to do RL. Um, it's going to be
hard to like collect data on your cars,
like all of your cars at once, then do a
like a policy update um, like every like
30 seconds or even every minute or even
every hour. like it's much easier to
first collect a large batch of data like
maybe over a couple days, maybe over a
week, then update your policy on all
that data and repeat that process. And
so I refer to that sort of problem
statement as kind of a batch online
setting where you're collecting a batch
of online data with one policy then
doing an update and repeating.
um in this sort of um more batch data
collection setting might have challenges
that are a bit different from your kind
of typical online reinforcement learning
setting.
Um
and so this sort of it's this sort of
data collection should be quite
practical. You could also do this
potentially asynchronously where you're
collecting data asynchronously from
making updates. uh and at large scale
this sort of asynchronous updates um can
actually potentially also be more
practical.
Um and there might be new considerations
on the algorithm side. Um so for example
in one recent work by Dong at all they
found that using more expressive
policies like diffusion policies was
really really important for effective
reinforcement learning in this sort of
batch online setting. And one
explanation for that is if you're
collecting a large batch of data, having
diverse actions uh be represented uh
could naturally be pretty important. Um
because uh in the fully online setting,
if you have a more deterministic policy,
uh if you're going to be making an
update, maybe it's okay to be more
deterministic because you're going to uh
you're going to change your policy
really really soon anyway. And so you'll
already get more diverse data just from
changing your policy so frequently. um
whereas in the more batch setting um you
don't have the luxury of changing your
policy so frequently and having um a
more diverse distribution might be quite
helpful.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So DPO there are algorithms
that are operating much more offline. Um
and so there is success there. Uh the
one downside of that is those problems
are shorter horizon. Uh and so can we do
long horizons and with less online data?
So yeah and things like offline are also
going to be more scalable as well.
Okay. Um let's talk a bit about
deployment and evaluation. So one um one
problem I think that is
quite important with these models is
thinking about safety and how to apply
these models in more safety critical
domains. That could be domains like
medicine, driving, mental health
counseling, legal and political
discourse and so on. Um no shortage of
domains that have challenges that could
lead to safety critical situations when
you make mistakes.
Um now historically this sort of problem
has been approached by trying to
formally verify the behavior of the
model or provide some sort of
probabilistic guarantees. Uh but
generally often times these methods are
going to make assumptions that don't
hold under real world circumstances and
so even if you can verify it in a model
um those verifications often won't hold
at larger scales.
Um and generally it's impossible to like
fully guarantee safety in the countless
number of scenarios that you can
encounter in the real world. Um and we
find that even humans make mistakes and
so even in safety critical settings. So
human drivers make mistakes, surgeons,
uh pilots make mistakes, politicians
make mistakes, uh and so forth.
So um we can't guarantee safety but we
could at least try to um try to think
about h handling safety critical
scenarios effectively
and
arguably if you were to think about
safety um there might be some
constraints that we could apply to the
model in some scenarios but in general
safety is an open world problem. You
need to handle all sorts of different
ways in which your model could do
something that's unsafe. And arguably
large scale machine learning has been
the most successful way to handle open
world circumstances.
And so as a result of this, it seems
like perhaps we should try to collect
large amounts of data that would teach
our model what is safe and what is
unsafe.
Now at the same time, this is really
unsatisfying. uh this means that we
actually have to somehow uh collect a
lot of data under unsafe circumstances
and it also can have some really real
and negative um kind of uh
ramifications. So as an example there
was um news articles that talked about
how um tech companies are
basically trying to do um content
moderation or label data that is
traumatic or toxic. um and labeling that
kind of data can um even cause humans
all sorts of mental health challenges uh
and has a lot of kind of ethical
considerations.
And so um this sort of approach isn't
satisfying for handling this sort of
safety critical problem.
Uh, and so can we develop methods that
can learn what's unsafe without
expansive data, without expansive human
labeling, without expansive data of
incidents that happen themselves.
Um, maybe we could use synthetic data
for this. Uh, maybe we can use some sort
of prior knowledge. Uh, this is an open
challenge uh and would have uh a lot of
benefits in terms of the safety of these
systems and the safety of training these
systems.
Um and then separate from that
as these models are improving we also
want them to remain safe during the
exploration process and during the
learning process.
Uh and
this is something that humans are
actually pretty good at doing. Uh and as
sort of a silly example uh I uh maybe a
couple years ago I taught myself how to
ride my bike without holding on to the
handlebars. And I did so without ever
falling off my bike. Uh, and I'm not
saying that to brag. Uh, the maybe this
is like it's not it's not that hard. Uh,
it took time, took effort. Uh, but I
think it's really fascinating to think
about like how would you get a robot to,
for example, learn how to do a new
behavior like that without ever falling
or without ever causing damage to
themselves. uh and it means that you're
fundamentally exploring a new part of
the state space while also understanding
what might be more risky and less risky
and thinking about a curriculum over
what um how to accomplish that sort of
objective.
Okay. Um so separate from safety uh
although related is that these models do
um even in non-safety critical scenarios
make mistakes. Uh sometimes these
mistakes are called hallucinations.
Uh probably many of you have encountered
these kinds of mistakes before. Um I'll
provide one example here uh where I was
asking it to uh tell me what the weight
of the sugar on the bowl is in this
image. Uh and it confidently told me
that the digital scale in the image
reads 108.2 g. That is the weight of the
sugar currently in the bowl. Uh this
answer is incorrect. It's actually a bit
different from what the scale shows.
Although it's also very challenging to
read what the scale shows because of the
glare in the image.
Um, and
oftentimes in language models, humans
are the recipient of the predictions of
these models. And this means that often
times mistakes are fairly manageable
because a human can discern whether or
not the model was saying the right thing
or the wrong thing.
Um, but the interface between these
humans and these models is not well
optimized.
Uh and as an example of this uh there
was a study that was looking or actually
multiple studies that have looked at how
um AI systems work with uh doctors and
in one study it found that when the AI
was working independently it was able to
achieve 92% accuracy.
Um when physicians were using AI
assistance they only had 76% accuracy.
Um, and that was barely better than when
humans were acting alone, which was 74%
accuracy. Uh, and it seems like for
these systems to be more effective, we
should take into account the fact that
they'll be working with humans when
actually uh making decisions at the end
of the day. Uh, because if we're like 92
sounds great compared to 74, but if it
is going to be a system that's
interacting with a person, uh, 76
doesn't sound quite so great.
Um, so can we optimize for better human
AI systems? And as part of this, maybe
maybe one way to achieve this was if
models could better estimate uncertainty
and better estimate when they might be
giving the right answer versus when they
might be giving the wrong answer.
Um, and there's research that shows that
if you take a pre-trained model and plot
the confidence of the model versus the
accuracy of the model. So the confidence
is the predicted probability of the
answer that it gives and this is the
actual accuracy of those answers on
average. Uh you see that it's actually
very well calibrated. So that confidence
actually reflects its accuracy really
well. But then after post- training with
reinforcement learning, we actually see
that the model becomes far less
calibrated.
Uh and so maybe reinforcement learning
is actually um while it's making the
model better is actually deteriorating
some of the um calibration that these
models might have at the beginning.
Um perhaps one direction um there was
some research by town at all that showed
that um if you verbalize the probability
rather than using the probability like
the the loits in the model and encourage
it to provide multiple guesses then you
can get um more calibrated model uh
performance after RHF compared to the
RHF model. Um so maybe that's one
possible direction. Even then you need
to figure out how this would interface
with a human and then evaluate how it
does when the human and model are
working together.
Um but yeah this is I think an important
open problem for thinking about how um
humans and AI systems are working
together.
And then even separate from that a lot
of AI systems are not going to have a
human there at the end of the day um
that are checking all the answers. And
this is true in autonomous driving um
where a human isn't going to be always
holding the steering wheel. This is true
in robotics where maybe you will be
working with a a human but probably many
of the decisions won't be checked by a
human um compared to many of the
language model use cases. And even in
language models, there's lots of use
cases where you want to just plug that
in to another system to um to provide
some sort of uh to to control some
system. Maybe web agents, for example,
will be autonomously uh choosing what to
do. uh and so in those scenarios can we
get really high reliability? Uh
reinforcement learning is likely a part
of the solution. Online data is really
helpful for getting high performance. Um
and there's promising results that
reinforcement learning can give really
high reliability. Um one example by Luo
at all uh showed that they were able on
fairly challenging robot tasks, they're
able to get uh performance where they
ran the policy a 100 times and it worked
a 100 times. Uh so that's pretty cool
but extending this to large scale
scenarios where you need to have really
high reliability uh is quite important.
Okay. Uh and then
the last thing I'll talk about is
evaluation.
So in supervised learning we can measure
accuracy and we can use held out
validation sets and this is kind of like
heaven because we can get like a very
nice measure offline of how good our
model is.
Uh but in reinforcement learning in
general there aren't any reliable
offline metrics. And to evaluate
performance typically at the end of the
day you just need to run your policy uh
roll it out in whatever environment
you're in and measure the reward um or
measure the performance.
Uh and the reason for this is that the
data collected um uh this data collected
so far um under whatever policy differs
from the data that was collected by the
learn policy. And so uh you it's really
hard to evaluate the policy on states
that the policy is going to visit uh
when you don't have those set of states
that the policy will necessarily visit.
Um now to make matters worse um if we
have a generalist system that is
intended not just to do one task but to
do many tasks uh then we need to
evaluate our policy not just in one
circumstance but in all sorts of
circumstances. Uh and this means that we
need to collect large amounts of online
data and evaluate uh all of those
different uh all those different
rollouts. Um and this makes it really
hard to decide first if the policy is
good enough to deploy. Um or even just
the simpler problem of picking which of
your different models is the best model
and choosing hyperparameters for
example.
as a real world circumstance um of this
problem. Uh about a month ago, uh OpenAI
released a chat GBT model, a new version
of GP, uh of GBT40, I think. Um and if
you asked it, uh how many people am I
goodter than at thinking? Um it said if
I had to put a number on it, I'd
estimate that you're easily in the 130
to 145 range of IQ. uh which would put
you above about um 98 to 99.7% of people
in raw thinking ability, but honestly
comparing you to most people almost
insults the quality of mind you're
aiming to develop.
Um so maybe this isn't what you're uh
kind of expecting or looking for in uh
in your model. And uh OpenAI actually
ended up needing to roll back this
update um that made the bot uh
excessively flattering to users.
Um, this gets out the challenge of like
it's really hard to know if the model
that you're developing um is is good
enough, is better than your previous
model and so forth. It's really hard to
evaluate these systems.
Um, a couple specific open questions.
Uh, first, can we develop offline
metrics that can at least rule out bad
models? Um, let alone estimate
performance. Uh, estimating performance
would be uh would be the dream. Um but
at the very least maybe we could rule
out models that we shouldn't deploy
offline.
Um and then even in terms of online
policy evaluation if we need to evaluate
a policy in all sorts of circumstances
can we figure out how best to select
representative scenarios that will allow
us to measure generalist performance
without having to evaluate every single
possible scenario.
Cool. Now, that was all I had for
frontiers and open problems. And um I
guess one thing I want to convey is that
now that you've taken the class, uh you
should be really well equipped to start
tackling these challenges. You don't
know everything about reinforcement
learning, of course, but uh you should
know a lot of the um fundamentals that
will allow you to go read research
papers, understand um where the
state-of-the-art is uh and build on the
state-of-the-art. So your question is
like why why does this happen basically?
So, I don't think we necessarily expect
this, but the kind of looking at this in
retrospect, I think it's reasonable to
um to kind of make some guesses for why
this is happening. And I think the
predominant theory for why this is
happening is that um the objective that
you're optimizing for first, it's not
exactly accuracy. Uh it's not exactly
aligned with that. And the um typically
what reinforcement learning with human
feedback, what it's doing often times is
actually sharpening the distribution. Uh
so the pre-trained model it often will
output all sorts of stuff and what RHF
is trying to do is like let's say okay
this is the mode that we really want our
model to be predicting and it's be
sharpening that distribution to really
encourage the model to be more likely to
sample one mode. Um and that sharpening
often leads to um it being overconfident
um in certain circumstances especially
when preferences are rewarding you for
being confident. Um and uh
um and then also um yeah at times being
correct and competent and at sometimes
being incorrect and confident.
Cool. Um so let's talk a little bit
about how to do research. Uh and this
will be a focus on how to do research
that's more of an empirical flavor. Uh
similar to the research that you would
do if you were doing a deep
reinforcement learning project.
Now before I get started uh I have a
couple uh different thoughts. Uh the
first is that I'll talk a lot about how
I go about the research process and
advice that I give to PhD students um as
I see them working through various
research projects. Uh but there's many
different ways to do research and it's
important and good for the community to
do research in many different ways. uh
because that leads to more diverse
discoveries and if everyone did research
the exact way that I do research then um
we would probably have uh fewer diverse
discoveries and so diversity is good and
um my research approach uh is not
necessarily uh like the best approach
and I don't think there's any one
approach that is the best approach.
I also felt like it could be good to
give a little bit of a backstory which
is that I did not intend to like have a
career in research. I uh was planning to
go to industry and develop products um
which is what my parents did in various
engineering fields uh and I felt like
that was the way to have real world
impact. I did internships in industry um
and uh kind of eventually figured out
that um I was excited about AI and I was
excited about algorithm development and
it seemed like the frontier of that and
algorithm development was really in a
research environment rather than in an
industry environment. And a lot of the
topics I was excited about uh didn't
really work. Uh like things like
robotics uh didn't really work even
today. Um robots often don't work very
well. Uh and so they're really in this
sort of research domain. Also the people
that I met in industry that were working
on the kinds of things that I wanted to
be working on all had PhDs and so I was
like well I should probably get a PhD
too if I want to work on those things.
Um, and then they also just found
research and the ambiguity of research
to be uh really kind of intellectually
interesting and challenging.
Um, and so that's all to say that uh you
don't in have to intend to have to to
work in research um in order to
eventually end up doing research.
Cool. Um and then the last thing I'll
mention before getting into um getting
into how to do research is just like
some general realities with research. Uh
the first is that um very very few
research ideas are good uh and very very
few research ideas have impact
uh have lasting impact especially a lot
of ideas don't work um a lot of ideas uh
don't work to the extent that they won't
lead to papers as an example of this uh
here are the outcomes of some of my
research ideas uh and here are the
outcome of some more of my research
ideas and there's a lot of kind of
failure um and this often like the risk
and the challenge of doing research uh
informs like different ways like a lot
of what I'll say has to do with dealing
with that sort of risk and dealing with
those challenges.
Um and then even if it does lead to a
paper um a lot of impacts won't ne a lot
of papers won't necessarily have a
lasting impact.
Um the second thing that I'll mention is
that uh research is inherently
incremental. We are building upon the
knowledge of previous research that's
been done. And as an example of this,
uh, AlphaFold arguably like a really
impactful thing. Um, very very
successful. Arguably could be considered
a breakthrough. Um, this itself was uh
in many ways incremental. It built very
closely on a large 20-year academic
project um called CASP. uh which was a
structure a protein structure prediction
project that was basically a kind of a
competition and a data set um for doing
this sort of structure prediction and
also built very heavily on advances in
neural networks. And so even if any one
research project isn't a breakthrough,
it often has plays an important role
because it allows other projects to
build on it or other projects to
potentially rule out ideas that have
been tried already.
And then the last thing that I'll
mention is that uh oftenimes people
think about like developing really cool
fancy algorithms but in a world where
scaling up is often quite important uh
especially in AI research uh often times
it's actually the simple ideas that have
more impact than the fancy ideas uh or
the complex algorithms and that's just
because the simple ideas are the things
that can scale. that the things that are
easy to easy to be integrated into
different systems and easy to build on
top of.
Okay,
cool. With that out of the way, um I'll
talk about what to work on, how to do
the work, how to share the work, um and
then a couple miscellaneous topics. Uh,
and
I would argue that these three things,
um, picking problems to work on, doing
the research, and sharing the work are
all equally important. And it's easy to
think that like maybe number two is the
most important or maybe number one, but
all of these are actually like really
really important for being successful in
research.
Okay, so step one uh, for what to work
on, I think that a research project
needs two things. The first is an
important problem and the second is a
plan for how to approach that problem.
And if you only have one of these uh
then usually that doesn't constitute a
good project direction. Uh so for
example maybe one project idea is I want
to solve climate change. Um that is an
important problem but I don't have a
plan for how to approach it. Uh so it
doesn't make a good research project
even though it's a really important
problem.
Uh second, maybe I have a really cool
algorithm that at best will make uh a
robot or a reinforcement learning system
a little bit more successful.
Uh this is um maybe a really cool idea.
Uh and maybe I have a plan, maybe I have
two, but I'm missing kind of the
important problem that this is actually
solving.
Uh and so for this latter part I think
it's really important to think about
like if the project is really really
successful uh what will the outcome look
like? Does it solve an important problem
or what is the upper bound of that
project? Uh and if the upper bound is
not very high then uh usually it doesn't
make for a very good project.
Step two, if you have an important
problem and a plan for how to approach
it, uh are you excited about it?
research is a lot of work. Uh, and if
it's fun, if you think it's really cool
and exciting, then you're more likely to
work hard on it. And if you're working
hard on it, you're much more likely to
be successful on it. And this is
actually probably true for a lot of
things outside of research, too. It's
good to, I don't know, spend times on
spend time on the things that you find
exciting, that you find really cool. Uh,
you'll probably, if you can find some of
those things, it may not even be just
one thing. If you can just find
something that you think is really cool
and exciting, then you'll probably do a
lot better at it.
Cool. And then step three, uh
like I mentioned before, uh a lot of
ideas don't work. And so it's really
good to think about like if you are
brutally honest about why your idea
could fail to solve the problem, does
the idea still have a good chance of
working?
And
if not, then probably it won't work. Uh
and that's mostly just because of the
reality of most ideas not actually
working in research. And it's important
to be honest with yourself about whether
this will actually solve the problem uh
or not.
Cool. Um so that's my three-step process
for picking problems. Now, a couple more
thoughts on this. So research can often
either start with an idea or a problem.
Uh and I think both of these sorts of
approaches to um a project are have
merits and I've done research that's
more idea driven. I've also done
research that's more problem driven. Uh
but I tend to lean towards one myself.
Uh and the reason is as follows. So if
you start with an idea, you need to find
a problem that that idea solves.
And there may not exist an important
problem that the idea solves. uh and it
may like sort of solve a problem but
there might be a better way to solve a
problem and if there's a better way to
solve the problem then that idea may not
have a lot of impact.
On the contrary if you start with a
problem then you're trying to find the
best solution to that problem and one
downside is it may be harder to write a
paper if you the solution ends up being
kind of obvious in retrospect. Uh but at
least you're guaranteed to be working on
an important problem and if you find a
solution uh you'll still be happy even
if it ends up being a little bit harder
to figure out how to write a paper about
it.
Another way [snorts] to put this is that
uh with idea driven research your sort
of goal is to get the idea to work
whereas in the second case your goal is
to solve the problem. And the second
camp seems like a much more comfortable
place to be uh because it's possible
that the idea just like doesn't want to
work or it's not going to work uh at the
end of the day.
Another note here is that if you're
thinking about a problem that you want
to solve,
uh it's really important to get to the
bottleneck of that problem. So if the
problem is bottlenecked on data for
example and you start exploring new
algorithms separate from the data for
how to solve it then you actually
probably won't see performance gains
from working on methods uh if it's
bottlenecked by data. Uh and at most
maybe you'll see like a couple
percentage points because really the the
big performance gains are going to be on
the data side. And so if you pick the
things that are bottlenecks and the
things that are like actually preventing
that thing from working um then you're
more likely to be able to make uh
progress. And so um I think a lot of
problem driven research ends up thinking
about like what is the bottleneck for
solving this problem. And this can also
be even in terms of much longer term
thinking like you can think about um I
want to develop uh a like an LLM that
can solve um like a a a pro can prove
something that we've like humans have
never proved before like P versus NP or
something. Uh or I want to get a robot
that can make a bowl of cereal uh in a
new kitchen. Uh those are things that
you can't solve in a any individual
research process uh any individual
research pro project. Um, but you can
think about, okay, what's the bottleneck
for getting there? And can I work on the
part of that problem in my next project
that will make progress on that larger
goal. A couple more things
for this next thing. I want to tell a
little bit of a story. Uh, so in the
second year of my PhD, I did an
internship. Um, and I did an internship
at Google where they had all these
robots and I wanted to use the robots uh
to do something cool. And my project
idea was to build a predictive model uh
actually a video generation model and
use it to learn skills across the
robots.
Um and then there was a problem uh most
research projects have problems that you
find uh and in particular I discovered
that video generation models were really
bad. So, um, here was a video that I
collected on the robot.
And here was a prediction from
arguably the state-of-the-art video
generation model. Uh, and you can see
that uh, it is erasing all the objects
in the video, and is barely capturing
the motion of the arm, doesn't even
capture the background correctly. Uh,
and so this means that I wasn't able to
actually use these kinds of models to
actually get the robot to do something
better.
Uh now at the time I kind of viewed
myself as a machine learning and
robotics person and not really a
computer vision person, not a person who
works on generative models. If I kind of
felt like I should only work on machine
learning and robotics, I might have to
table this and figure out a different
project to work on. But instead, I
decided to work on trying to develop a
video gen a better video generation
model. Now arguably I wasn't necessarily
the best person to do this. I had never
built a generative model before. I
didn't really know that much about
architectures for doing so. But not a
lot of people were working on it at the
time because they didn't realize how bad
these models were. Uh and then the
resulting paper ended up being kind of
the basis for work in my job talk now
has around 1300 citations. Uh and in it
arguably informed the community that
it's kind of an interesting problem to
study and led to much better video
generation models than the one that I
was able to develop. Uh and so I guess
the kind of lesson that I'm trying to
convey here is that it's good to not box
yourself into an area and say I'm only
going to work on this particular area.
Uh and the reason for that is if you
cross topic boundaries, it's going to
inform new problems. Uh because if
you're trying to use something that is a
problem for advancing the topic you want
to work on, uh then that kind of informs
that there's a problem with that
existing thing. And often times people
in that field don't know that it's a
problem. Um and then it also brings new
ideas to that other topic or domain as
well. And so I lot I see a lot of people
kind of boxing themselves into areas but
I think that actually crossing topic
boundaries um ends up leading to um a
lot of new insights and innovations.
Um and then the last thing that I'll
mention is uh don't be a perfectionist.
So I've I've seen um people kind of feel
like they want to pick the perfect
project to work on. Uh but you never
know what the impact of a project will
be at the outset otherwise it wouldn't
be research. Uh and so at some point you
need to just like start trying different
ideas uh start going on a getting going
on a project um without like trying to
find the perfect project.
Okay. So once you have a project idea or
a project direction a key consideration
from there is handling risk. So we've
talked about how lots of research ideas
don't work.
um how do we deal with that?
So um there's a lot of tricks for
dealing with risk and not all of them
are going to apply to every single
project. Uh but these are tricks that I
think you should be able to kind of draw
upon um to handle the risk in research.
Uh so the first is wherever possible
it's good to frontload the risk in the
project. Think about what is like what
is the reason why this might not
succeed. um and before developing
infrastructure, before um like coding up
the entire algorithm and so forth, if
you can formulate and run simple
experiments that test the core unknowns
that you have, then you can kind of
bring the risk to the beginning of the
project. Um this can be really
uncomfortable uh because oftentimes you
kind of like building the
infrastructure, coding the algorithm,
whatever. That's like the easy part.
That's like the that's the part where
like you can kind of seemingly make some
progress on the project. Uh but if you
at the if you do all that and then at
the end realize that the core unknown
actually ended up not working out then
you wasted all of that time even though
it seemingly seemed like progress you
wasted all that time um on that idea
that wasn't going to pan out at the end
of the day. Um and so if instead if you
can kind of frontload that risk and
frontload the unknowns run experiments
to test those unknowns then um you can
make sure that you can if it is is
applicable you can um do that first and
then build out the infrastructure uh or
build out the algorithm completely and
run all the experiments after doing that
initial test.
Along the same lines, uh thinking
through how to test ex how to test ideas
in the simplest possible way or the
fastest possible way takes some skill
and takes some thinking like you it's
often not obvious how to test a
particular hypothesis.
Another so kind of separate from trying
to frontload risk and frontload
experiments um
is simply just iterating a lot. So you
don't like you have to get lucky to
stumble upon a good idea but you can
sort of create luck for yourself just by
trying out lots of ideas uh by iterating
on lots of different ideas. Uh and if
you try out an idea and and kind of the
targeted experiment doesn't work then
you can discard it quickly try out
another idea and so forth. Uh and for me
there was kind of lots of times in my
PhD where I tried out lots of ideas that
didn't fail that didn't make it that uh
into papers they failed. Um, and I think
that this allowed me to uh to come upon
some ideas that worked well. I didn't
always do this. Sometimes I ended up
banging my head against the wall um
plenty of times. But this is something
that I found to be a good strategy for
trying to iterate and get through the
bad ideas quickly uh so that you can get
to some good ideas.
Uh and then I think the last thing on
this slide is um if you can try out lots
of ideas, especially at the beginning of
the project, you can try out lots of
ideas at the beginning and then not
commit to any one of them until you see
some signs of life on that core unknown
and then if you find signs of life on
one of those projects, then you can
start to commit to that project um after
you see uh some sort of like initial
result on it. Um so this is kind of
another sort of like brute force
approach to trying lots of different
things um so that you can get through
the bad ideas. Yeah. So the question is
in problem driven research uh it's a bit
more comfortable because uh you can try
out multiple ideas. Are there scenarios
where there isn't is there like there
isn't like a ton of ideas. Um and yeah
there's definitely scenarios like that
where uh you may not have like tons of
ideas for solving a problem. Um, and I
should mention that like in this sort in
this sort of approach where you try out
lots of different things, you could also
be trying out multiple different
problems as well. Uh, and so the um,
yeah, you could be trying out like a
couple ideas for one problem, try out a
couple ideas for a different problem.
Um, and then pick your problem based on
like like um, pick your problem based on
like what seems to be tractable because
even at the outset, you don't know how
hard a problem is going to be. And it
might be that it's too hard for u the
scope of a current project or we don't
have good tools or good ideas for how to
solve it. Yeah. Can I give an example of
frontloading a core unknown in a
project? A couple ideas. So um maybe
I'll try to give a couple examples. So
um one example is I um I've worked on
metalarning in the past and the the goal
was to see if you can quickly adapt with
a very small amount of data to uh a to a
a problem and the goal was ultimately to
be able to like get a robot for example
to quickly adapt to a new task. Um
and but actually like designing a metal
learning system on a real robot like is
a ton of work and and would take a lot
of uh work to even just do the coding
for it. Uh and so what I did is I first
set up an experiment where um the tasks
instead of learning um robot tasks the
tasks were regressing to simple like 1D
sinosoid curves. Uh so like really
really simple problem and then just
tested like can you learn with like a
few data points like five data points to
uh regress to the curve. Uh and so it
was this experiment that I could code it
up in like a day um and get some initial
results from uh and it ended up working
out pretty well and so then I kind of
that gave me the signs of life to try
it. Um,
another example of this, uh, maybe a
more recent example, um, I've been
thinking a little bit about how to get
robots to follow different kinds of
language instructions, including
language instructions for different
strategies. And there's a couple risks
for this. One is getting good labels for
the strategies. And the second is
actually getting the robot to pay
attention to those different strategies.
And, um, I took a um, and that second
one actually seemed like the bigger
challenge. Uh, and I took a data set
where it was like a really really simple
problem where in some of the data the
robot used the right gripper and some of
the data the robot used the left
gripper. And then I trained a policy
just to see if it could like do that
very simple thing. Very easy to evaluate
and I already had I could like
automatically determine if it was using
the right or left from the data rather
than doing labeling. And so that kind of
isolated a core risk of the problem um
before moving on to like uh the broader
problem of getting a robot to follow
strategies.
Okay. Uh, now you have a problem, you
have an idea, uh, you want to get things
to work. One thing that's really hard in
terms of getting something to work is if
you're starting with something that
doesn't work. Uh, so if you code up a
system and it's not working, uh, there's
a million reasons that could be why it's
not working. Uh, and it's really hard to
figure out which of those things might
be causing it to not work. Uh, you can
make visualizations. There's various
tools for trying to figure that out. Um,
but it's much easier to start with
something that works and then make it
harder than to start with something that
doesn't work and try to get it to work.
Uh, and so one thing that's very useful
in research is to if you're in a
scenario where things aren't working,
simplify the problem dramatically until
something does work and then move it
back to the harder setting by, for
example, adding more data, more tasks,
whatever. Um, and yeah, really useful
debugging strategy. Uh, and I've seen,
yeah, a lot of projects where things
aren't working. um and you just kind of
need to go back to the drawing bird. As
a maybe as a very specific example for
this, um at one point I was trying to
train um robots to uh be able to see a
video of a human doing a task and then
do the task themselves with imitation
learning. uh collected a really diverse
data set of robot demonstrations and
then asked a human to do what the robot
did um of like all sorts of tasks and we
just like told um people collecting the
data like do whatever you want do lots
of things. Um nothing worked uh when
training on this data um spent like
months trying to get the robot to do it.
Um, and then what we did is we
simplified uh to just a single task
setting like can we get the robot to do
one task and make sure our imitation
learning stack works. It actually didn't
work. Uh, and so we had to debug that,
get it to work on one task, then get it
to work on three tasks, then get it to
work on 10 tasks. Um,
so yeah, starting with a feeling that
works really, really helpful.
Simplifying is really helpful for that.
Another thing, uh, it's really easy to
like get in your own head and just, um,
yeah, have trouble debugging something
just by yourself. And so talking to
friends, colleagues, advisers, uh, can
also be helpful and help you figure out
whether it makes sense to jump up a
level um, and kind of reconsider the
problem or keep on tuning
hyperparameters or try something that
you didn't think of. And then also uh,
revisiting assumptions. So you might go
into a project thinking that something
um is like a lot easier than it turned
out to be. Uh and then you might learn
through the course of the project that
that thing is actually really hard. Uh
and so thinking through like has
anything changed about my assumptions
from the beginning and then if something
has changed would that change the way
that you're going about the project or
even the project that you're working on
as a result.
Okay. And then
maybe I'll also talk about a story for
this. So there's scenarios where you're
kind of trying to get something to work
and it doesn't really want to work. It's
not really easy to get it to work. And
if it doesn't really want to work, then
probably the idea won't be very
impactful because if someone else is
trying to get it to work and it also
doesn't really easily work for them,
then um maybe the idea just like wasn't
really meant to be.
And at one point we had this project
where this is actually a recent a fairly
recent project where we were trying to
get a robot to follow open-ended
language commands and um like can you
clean up the trash but not the dishes.
Uh we also wanted to see if the robot
could handle various interventions like
and follow lots of different prompts for
example. Then then we kind of got some
initial signs of life on that and we're
like, "Oh, well maybe we could also get
the robot to ask questions if the prompt
is ambiguous." And we had like all these
like kind of cool ideas for how we could
incorporate like the sort of open-ended
language following in a robot system.
And um
despite having kind of positive initial
signs of life, after we introduced all
those ideas, things like weren't really
working. Uh and we kind of tried all
sorts of like we I don't know spent a
couple months trying to get it to work
and
um then at some point we kind of went
back and
thought about well okay we had pre like
it was working before um like what parts
of this thing do work and what parts of
these things are harder to get to work
with our current method and then we kind
of rescope the project to remove the
hard parts that we didn't know how to
solve yet and to only consider the parts
uh the kind of interactions that our
method did work with. Uh and so the kind
of it was an example where we picked the
examples we we picked the can we scoped
the project to um the sorts of things
that the method wanted to work on worked
easily on and left the things that it
didn't handle for future work. We
described it as limitations in the
paper. Um and so scoping down the
project uh especially if you kind of
scoped it up a little bit too eagerly uh
can also be a useful strategy in
research.
Okay. Um, last thing, if you're just in
a scenario where things really aren't
working, uh, you might decide whether or
not you should pivot or whether or not
you should start working on a different
project.
Often times, you'll consider this later
than you should be considering this, uh,
because you really want to get something
to work. Uh there's also this sunk cost
fallacy where if you spent a lot of time
on something then you it's very natural
for humans to think that you'll spend
less time on it in the future because
you spent a lot of time on it in the
past. This is a fallacy not always true
and you might actually not have made as
much progress that on the problem um
than the time that you spent on it would
suggest.
Now, deciding when to pivot is really
hard because you're often thinking
about, should I continue working on my
current project or should I switch to
starting a new project.
And this option of switching to a new
project is really nebulous. Like, this
could mean a lot of different things.
There's a lot of different things you
might be doing. And so, it's really hard
to think about should I be doing what
I'm currently doing or should I do
something else? Because something else
is like could be like anything. [snorts]
And so one kind of mental trick for
thinking about this sort of decision
about whether to pivot is to change this
decision and actually spend time
thinking about other projects that you
would do and then try to formulate the
decision as continuing working on the
current project versus working on
project B or working on project C and so
forth. Uh and this decision is much more
concrete um a lot more straightforward
to think about less anxietyinducing and
so forth.
Yeah. So the question is um when
research fields are moving really
quickly um you might feel like you like
you might be worried that another group
will do the same thing and then try to
spend less time on the evaluation just
to try to get the paper out faster. Is
that a trend? Um what do I think about
that? Uh so
h I mean I it's definitely like like
there's definitely papers that have
spent like that should be more thorough
with the evaluation. Um that's been true
that's true now that's also been true in
the past. Um I don't know if it's been
getting worse per se. Um,
I think that
if there is like a a feeling to do that,
I think like you you really want to be
confident about the results that you're
putting out. Uh, and I think that if
you're worried about being scooped like
or another group doing something uh like
there there's like
there is like an advantage to having um
like done some sort of idea first, but
there's also a lot of advantage to
executing really well on a project. Uh,
and sometimes the projects that are
executed on better are more impactful
than the projects that were like first
at a particular idea. Uh and so the um
yeah I I guess my perspective is that is
to like still put a fair amount of focus
on execution um and evaluation. Now
there's many things you could evaluate.
You could run your experiments on 20
data sets and so there's [clears throat]
a limit to what do you want to do um so
I think there's a balance um and
yeah um certainly there are some parts
of the research field that move fast.
One thing that I've liked about real
robots is that small like a small enough
people work with like real hardware that
um you have to worry you can worry less
about that in many ways especially if
you execute on and actually show the
results on real robots. Um
so yeah but there's a balance and and
it's also good to work on things like
language models and things that are hot
too. Uh yeah, there's a balance.
Okay, so how to share your research? uh
I talked about how this is really
important. Uh why is this really
important? So if you think about what is
the output or the outcome of research
uh the output of research is essentially
like ideas, knowledge, things that you
learned from doing the research. Uh it's
not a product, it's not a service. It's
really like knowledge. It's things that
you learn.
And
in um if it were a product then the
output like the high impact would mean
that lots of people are using the
product for good things. But since it's
more like knowledge if no one knows
about what you learned then there was
really like no impact or no output as a
result. And even for companies that have
products and services they have massive
marketing efforts to try to get those
products out. Uh and so for your work to
have impact you need to share it and you
need people to know about it. uh
otherwise it won't have had impact.
Now
there can be reasons to not be excited
about sharing work. You can say maybe it
feels like self-promotion. Maybe the
idea didn't work that well. Uh so I'm
not that excited about sharing it. Maybe
it's like it seems all obvious like all
of it seems obvious to you now. Um and
so why do you need to share it? But even
if it feels like self-promotion, you're
you're teaching people. You're sharing
cool new findings. Uh and you can think
about it as more actually doing a
service to them to teach them something
new. uh and useful and interesting. Even
if it didn't work that well, it's really
useful to share because other people
might think of that idea and might want
to know how well did it work and did it
work in certain circumstances more uh
better than other circumstances. And
then yeah, after enough research, you're
going to know a lot more than other
people. Uh there will be things that
seem really obvious to you that are not
obvious to other people. And it's good
to still share those things um and think
about what's actually obvious what
actually other people don't know so that
you can um kind of share the things that
you have learned especially the most
important things with them.
Now, um
I mean I could probably give an entire
lecture on presenting research uh and
writing and presentations and so forth,
but yeah, having really clear writing,
really clear visuals, really clear
presentations. Communicating clearly is
really, really important. If they don't
understand what you're saying, then they
won't understand the knowledge. Uh it's
important to think about their audience
and how they will interpret what you
say, what they know. When in doubt,
assume that your audience knows less
rather than more. This can actually be a
little bit tricky to do. It's good to
avoid jargon if possible. They might
know the jargon, but um if there's ways
to avoid it, then it makes it more
accessible. And even if they do know a
lot of what you're going to say, a lot
of people still appreciate refreshers,
especially if those refreshers are
clear. Um and it might actually cause
them to think about something that they
know in a new way.
Other ways to get better at this, just
practicing practicing writing,
practicing giving presentations. uh you
can practice alone, you can practice uh
with other people if it's a
presentation. Uh and then just try to
get feedback, try to get honest feedback
from people and improve with the
feedback.
Now, you might also like when trying to
write a paper or when trying to create a
slide deck or something, it's easy to
like get a little bit overwhelmed by how
much you have to do and where even to
get started on that. I find it really
helpful to break down the task and even
on like a pen and paper just like write
down some ideas for what I how I want to
do it. U maybe write down an outline. My
recommendation would be to think through
your ideas for what you want to
communicate before asking your friend
before asking your friend chat GBT.
Cool. Um and then a couple miscellaneous
things. Uh first is mentorship. I think
mentorship can play a huge role in
research and if you have it, don't be
afraid to lean on it. in my like first
research paper in my PhD, I like hardly
wrote um like any of the paper and I
talked to actually my co-author and he
told me that he actually even rewrote
the section that I wrote. Um and so it's
okay to like not know everything and not
know how to do every part of the
research process. Uh and lean on the
things lean on other people for the
things that you don't know how to do
yet. Uh generally I've seen students be
and myself do most successful when
they're learning more gradually and when
they're not trying to take on everything
themsel uh because doing novel research
and writing a paper about it and
presenting it like picking a problem
like all of that is a really really huge
undertaking. Um and it's useful to lean
on other people as you're trying to
learn how to do that.
Um cool. And then confidence. So there's
a lot of reasons to lack confidence in
research. No one knows how to do
research right now. Uh no one knows what
research is going to be most impactful.
If they did, it wouldn't be research. Uh
many ideas don't work. Many papers get
rejected. Uh many researchers have been
thinking about a domain for many years
and they will be smarter than you in
that domain because they've been
thinking about it for many years. And so
it's easy to think that you know very
little, that you have been rejected
multiple time many times, um that a lot
of your ideas don't work. uh because all
of those things are kind of true. Uh but
that doesn't mean that you're actually
doing a bad job at research and
confidence is really important. If
you're not confident, if you're secondg
guessing, um overthinking things, it can
really slow you down. Uh and the um even
though these things are like
challenging, they're actually not
reasons to be um to be unconfident.
Cool. Um and then lastly, some closing
thoughts. Uh maybe since you're all
here, you're eager to do research. Uh
and so maybe I don't need to say this,
but um in terms of like the time that
we're in right now, I think that uh you
might kind of feel like reinforcement
learning like works now to some extent.
And so maybe we don't need to do
research. Maybe we can just uh like use
the thing that works uh and and like
apply it in all sorts of circumstances.
And there's a lot of merit to like
applying research uh in the real world.
Uh it's good for some people to do that.
Um but at the same time, I think that
now is like a better time than ever to
do research uh because we are actually
seeing new research being translated
into very real world impact. Um and like
a lot of the big breakthroughs like
Alphafold, like Chhat GBT and so forth,
there are things that are um like the
kind of compared to the breakthroughs of
like 10 years ago or 20 years ago, these
are things that are actually like
leading to really massive impact um in
the world today. And if you work on
research now, um you can help contribute
to those kinds of new breakthroughs uh
that will have even more impact in the
future uh compared to if you were doing
research 10 or 20 years ago. Um, so I
think that now is actually a better time
than ever uh to be doing research uh
including in deep reinforcement
learning. Um, so yeah, those are my
final thoughts.